[instrumental music]
[door closes]
- Hey, you.
- Hi.
[footsteps]
- Oh, hey.
- Hey, thought you'd gone home.
I wish.
We're up.
There's a double
homicide in Rancho Rosa.
Local sheriff's
in over his head.
- I'm on it.
- Boss.
You've been promising
me more time in the field.
- Now's as good a time as any.
- You're right.
Rigsby, be a cover
in the office on this one.
Let's go.
You're okay with this,
I hope?
Absolutely, yeah.
[police radio]
[indistinct conversations]
[Patrick]
'What's going on?'
Looks like two bullets
to the chest for each of them.
Freshness of the wounds
suggests
it happened
in the last few hours.
Selby and Jana Vickers,
33 and 31 years old
from here in Rancho Rosa.
Sheriff ID'd them
from their driver's licenses.
- Who found the bodies?
- 'Couple of teenagers.'
This place is a local lover's
lane, apparently.
Thieves know that, too.
Sheriff thinks that
it's a robbery gone sour.
Little old to be necking,
aren't they?
There's an age limit on that?
Plus their clothes aren't,
you know, disheveled.
Good point.
Oh, there's a little
white thing there sticking
out from Jana's dress.
'Could you just..
Yeah that's it.'
- $800 dress.
- Aha!
Is that a useful "aha"
or an irritating "aha"?
The borrowed dress tells us
they were going somewhere fancy
and wanted to make
an impression.
Not usually
something they'd go for
or they'd have
a later model car.
He needed a few pulls
on the scotch
just to take the edge off
because he was nervous
about who was gonna be there
which in a small town
like this
likely means relatives
or people from his past.
Uh, wedding, maybe?
Or birthday party?
No gift, which leaves..
- No guessing games.
- Aye..
Excuse me, sheriff, what's the
name of the local high school?
[Martha Wash singing
"Everybody Dance Now"]
♪ Everybody dance now ♪♪
[indistinct conversations]
Stephanie?
Oh, my God.
You look fantastic.
I'm sorry.
I'm not Stephanie.
Whoa.
Do that again,
and I'll arrest you.
Sorry, I-I had to.
You've always been the one.
[men laughing]
No way.
I'm not the one.
[sighs]
[indistinct conversations]
[Patrick]
'High school.'
Best years of your life.
Huh?
[theme music]
[indistinct conversations]
Welcome back
to Rancho Rosa High.
Go, Toros!
I'm Tess, one of your student
ambassadors this weekend.
Nametags and reunion books.
We're with the California Bureau
Of Investigation.
We need to know
if Jana and Selby Vickers
were expected here tonight.
Um..
Yeah, Selby Vickers
and his wife Jana.
They also replied "yes"
to tomorrow's
homecoming picnic and dance.
Is everything okay?
Oh, we need to talk to somebody
who would know them.
Um...
Red-headed woman,
that's Willa Brock.
'She's the reunion
committee chair.'
You didn't really think
we were young enough
to be in this class
when we walked in, did you?
Oh, everyone over the age of 21
looks the same to me.
Tactful and evasive.
You're gonna do very well
in life, Tess.
Go, Toros.
I'm stunned.
I mean, it was surprising enough
Selby was even coming.
- Now this?
- Oh, why the surprise?
Well, he wasn't at the fifth
or the tenth.
- Because..
- Because he was expelled.
And never graduated.
'Selby pulled this,
this really nasty prank.'
- What was it, senior year?
- Yeah.
It was his one and only,
Vice Principal DeSouza
caught him, gave him
the ol' boot.
What was the prank?
Uh, there was this,
shall we say
socially challenged boy
named Derek Logan.
Selby dragged him
into the girls' locker room
he blindfolded him
with his own underwear
tied him up, naked
took his picture and then
posted it all over the school.
I mean, how sick
is that, right?
It was disturbing.
Hmm. Uh, is there anything else
you can tell us about him?
'I played football.'
Starting running back.
People around here
are still talking about
the five touchdowns
I scored against Stratton.
What does that
have to do with Selby?
'I was popular.'
I was a jock.
He was a nobody.
I don't know
what kind of person he was.
How about his current life?
I got nada. I got out of
this town as fast as I could.
I live down
in Newport Beach now.
Hmm.
How about you, Willa?
Have you heard anything
about Selby?
Oh, I host a daytime
talk show in Chicago
that tapes two shows a day
and is about to go national.
I'm lucky if I hear anything
about my own family.
Uh, Derek Logan, the kid
that Selby pulled the prank on.
Could you
point him out to us?
[Gabe]
'Derek Logan?'
He's not here, is he?
No way!
Gabe, it's so good
to see you again.
You almost didn't.
Five hours I spent
on the 101 driving here.
CBI agent Teresa Lisbon,
Patrick Jane.
- This is Gabe Nyland.
- Hi.
DA for San Diego County.
'And you've prosecuted
a couple of cases for us.'
And now candidate
for lieutenant governor
of California.
Give me the word, G,
I start twisting arms for you
on election day, huh?
Um, Gabe, Selby Vickers
and his wife
were found murdered
at the Glen, shot in their car.
My, god.
I hadn't even heard that name
in 15 years till tonight.
Any idea who did this?
It's early
in the investigation.
- Hey, you just got here, right?
- Yes.
So how is it that you knew
Derek Logan wasn't here?
Well, Derek left the school
and moved out of state
after that prank Selby pulled.
- Word is, he killed himself.
- 'Are you serious?'
I heard he was a blackjack
dealer at a casino.
Uh, we'd like to talk
to some classmates
that still live in the area.
Maybe they know something
about Selby.
Well, there are only a few
but, uh,
the student ambassadors
can probably point you
in the right direction.
Thank you for your time.
[intense music]
Nothing jumps out on this
but I'm gonna have
the tech guys
give it a once-over.
Mail's all big bills
and small bank accounts.
They certainly weren't
living the high life here.
They didn't need to.
This was home. They were happy.
[cell phone ringing]
Agent Grace Van Pelt.
[Rigsby on phone]
'Hey. So I got you next of kin
info on Selby.'
Uh, mother in Rancho Rosa.
No luck on Jana, though.
Thanks.
Text me the address?
'Will do.'
So I've never been
to Rancho Rosa before.
What's it like?
Nothing special.
A town.
Cool. What are
you guys doing now?
You know, investigating.
Van pelt, come here.
Check this out.
- I gotta go.
- Y-yeah.
I'm-I'm busy...too.
[exhales deeply]
[Cho]
'This is from
yesterday morning.'
[man on the phone recorder]
'I'm done playing games here.
You hear me?'
'Either you get me my money
or I'm gonna be forced'
'to take action.'
[beeping]
So much for happiness.
Mm.
So you haven't seen Selby
once in all these years?
Supermarket,
movie theater maybe?
No. I mean, you know,
if I did, I-I don't remember.
Hard to believe you, Stu.
I'm sorry?
Well, uh, really?
Okay.
Yeah?
The hair plugs, the heels
this, uh,
professional woman here
posing as your girlfriend..
Wait, wait.
What did you just say?
- Whoa.
- D-did he just call me..
- What did you say..
- I-I mean..
That's all we need
for your time.
- I mean, all the questions.
- Beg my pardon.
That's all we have for now.
Thank you.
I think you look lovely.
Have a good evening.
Go, Toros.
What's your problem?
Uh, it's just a room
full of people lying
to each other.
Everyone here is trying so hard
to show how much they've changed
when the mere effort
screams that they haven't.
Or they actually
do change
with exceptions like
Mr. Hair Plugs, of course.
[Lisbon]
'You got the rebel
who took the bank job.'
'The player that
stays faithful to his wife.'
The rebel took the bank job
because she sees
her rebellion is fruitless.
The player stays faithful
to his wife
because the consequence
of infidelity
is much greater now.
But their instincts, their
instinctsnever change.
I'm a far cry from
what I was in high school.
Yeah, I wouldn't be so sure.
Driven to succeed to the point
of developing an ulcer.
No tolerance for superiors
less sharp than yourself.
Shutting out girls that
wanted to hang out with you.
Blowing off boys
that want to get close.
All the while,
at every turn, wondering
what is it I really want?
- No.
- And you played an instrument.
My guess?
Hmm. Clarinet.
Not even close.
And we're done here.
I'll get the guest list
to Rigsby.
I'll have him check
everybody out.
Have him locate
the whereabouts
of Derek Logan.
Ah, you really think Logan
laid in wait for 15 years
and suddenly decided
to take revenge on Selby?
Well, I think that
Logan is as angry today
as he was 15 years ago,
maybe even angrier.
We'll check him out.
You know, I'm gonna
stick around.
I-I didn't go to high school
this is kind of
fascinatingfor me.
You never went
to high school?
- No, I was busy.
- You can stay.
Just don't
make me sorry I let you.
Bassoon.
Mrs. Vickers,
when was the last time
you spoke to your son?
Um, this morning.
Selby always checks
in on me before he goes to work
to see how I'm doing.
He's..
He was sweet like that.
Were you aware of any
problems he was having?
Work? Personal life?
Um, no.
Just the opposite.
Things were starting
to get good for him.
After he left high school,
things didn't go right for him.
About high school,
the prank he pulled--
- I don't wanna talk about that.
- 'Ma'am.'
His whole life was spoiled
by that-that incident.
He lost a chance at college.
He-he got stuck working
in a little print shop.
And then Jana came along,
and..
...and she was like a whole
new world for him.
She encouraged him
and she told him to-to strive
for something better
and-and he became
a whole new person.
We haven't been able
to track down
any family for Jana.
Do you know
where we can find them?
She didn't have anybody.
Uh, nobody that I know of.
She'd moved here from Poland
and Selby only met her
a couple of months ago.
A few dates and...and they
got married.
It was all
kind of a whirlwind.
Now, Mrs. Vickers,
it's a bit unsettling
but I'd like you to listen
to this message
see if you recognize
the caller, is that all right?
Yeah.
[man on the phone recorder]
'I'm done playing games here.
You hear me?'
'Either you get me my money
or I'm gonna be forced'
'to take action.'
[beeps]
Well, I-I've never heard
that voice in my life.
Was my son involved with
a loan shark or something?
Could be, we traced
the phone call
to a phone booth
in Gallatin.
- 'That doesn't really tell us.'
- Gallatin?
Th-that's where Jana's from.
Uh, Se-Selby met her there
at a coffee shop
when he was on
a delivery run.
Can you tell us anything
about Jana
before she met Selby?
Maybe names of friends,
where she worked?
No, all that Selby told me
was that things
were tough for her.
Yeah, he didn't share
any details
probably, 'cause he didn't
want me making any judgments.
You remember
what we used to call you?
You were the frogman.
Frog because you played
the French horn.
Well, 'cause, you know
y-you kinda sorta look like
a frog, but no offense, but..
Yeah, no, I-I remember.
Oh, man, we used to
get on you.
You know what?
I'm sorry about that.
Sincerely, but I mean,
what?
We were kids, right?
We were just kids.
Forget it, forget it.
I have.
Dude, that-that time we put
the dead bird in his locker.
Oh, we did that.
Yeah, yeah, you guys
got me with that one.
Does anybody still call you
that, "the frogman"?
Well, pretty much everyone
calls me Phil
except my son,
who calls me dad.
You fathered a kid?
He fathered a..
Go, frogman!
Come on. Nice!
Good job.
Didn't think you had it in you.
Wait. Does he play
the French horn, too?
Because if he does,
you could call him frog boy
or...Kermit.
Or Kermie.
Really good to, uh,
see you guys again.
Come on, hey,
if the kid of yours
ever needs any shaping up
you send him to
a Cordova Sports Camp, okay?
[laughter]
Vodka tonic, please.
- Uh, top shelf.
- 'You got it.'
It's on me.
Thank you.
Um...you're one of the
uh, one of
the CBI people.
Yeah.
I heard about
what happened to Selby.
That's-that's awful.
Hmm. Well, it doesn't appear
to have dampened the mood here.
L.J. Cordova seems to be
having a great time.
Yeah, frogman..
[sighs]
If I could go back in time
and beat the crap
out of him
the first time
he called me that..
It's not possible, Phil.
Oh, I know.
But you could
just talk to him quietly
and tell him how you feel.
[scoffs]
He'd probably just laugh at me.
Probably.
But at least you would know
that you made an effort, right?
And this is a, what?
It's a 15 year school reunion.
What are these reunions for,
anyway?
[laughs]
I don't know.
I understand.
All those nights you lay there
not being able to sleep
thinking about whether or not
you should've confronted him.
It's tough.
You know what?
[clicks tongue]
You're right.
You go, Phil.
- Hey, L.J.
- What up, frog?
[Stu]
'What's your problem, man?'
- Oh, phil.
- Stop, come on.
- Get off me!
- Come on. What are you..
Phil.
[grunting]
[glass shatters]
Oh! Oh!
[man grunting]
- Aah!
- Oh! Oh.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
- You get off, now!
- Aah! Ohh! Get off! Get off!
[female #1]
Come here! Get off!
[glass shatters]
[instrumental music]
You know, this thing is
a golden treasury of mullets.
A brawl?
You started a brawl?
Come on.
Well, I was, uh,
I was going for something
a little more contained
but I guess people
just wanted to explore
the physical.
And what information
did you glean?
I assume you were testing
some theory or other?
Wow, Willa Brock
was involved
in eight different school
activities and she looked
pretty good in cargo pants
which is hard to do.
There are people
in the hospital.
Yes, but souls were healed.
This was a cathartic brawl.
It was-it was
a therapeutic expression of..
[footsteps]
- Please.
- Got a lead.
Jana's INS entry records
list a Gallatin address
as her destination.
The property and residence
of a Terence Badali.
No real sheet, but he had
a couple restraining orders
from women back in the '90s.
He could be our angry caller.
Go to Gallatin.
Take Van Pelt with you.
Okay.
You go to hell.
Take a toothbrush.
Which way is that?
I'll go.
[laughs]
What's so funny?
"If I want culture
I'll leave my yogurt
out overnight."
L.J. Cordova's
yearbook photo quote.
Well, when you're done
entertaining yourself
I got your Derek Logan
update right here.
Ah.
Kid's life never turned
the corner.
Derek Michael Logan
left Rancho Rosa
a couple weeks
after the Selby incident.
Family moved to Virginia.
He became a heroin addict.
Couple years
in and out of rehab.
He died of an overdose
on his 23rd birthday.
School office has sent over
his old student ID.
- From their archives?
- Mm-hmm.
[Patrick]
'Hmm, he kind
of looks like you.'
And, uh, this is
the photo of the incident
that, uh, Selby plastered
around the school.
How does any kid recover
from that?
Well, in this case,
they don't.
Mm.
- How sad.
- 'Mm.'
And I was betting
on Derek Logan as our killer.
Will you quit yanking
me around?
Okay, if you can't get it right,
we're through.
Now the order
was for 5/16th beech wood
not for 5/16th warped
beech wood.
Hey, Terence Badali?
CBI.
Need to talk to you about
Jana Vickers.
I'll call you back.
What about her?
You left
a threatening message
on her answering machine
recently.
Well, how do you know
it was me?
Because an innocent person
would say, I didn't do it.
So what? I called her.
Big deal.
You called her
and threatened her
now she and her husband have
been found killed, and so..
[screams]
[grunts]
You're under arrest.
[groans]
I panicked.
As soon as you told me they
were dead
I knew you were gonna
blame me
and my brain said, "just run."
Your brain's a fool.
Where were you last night?
I was watching college ball.
Can you prove that?
Notre Dame sucked.
I live alone..
...since that polish
bitch left me.
She and you had
a sexual relationship?
Well, she was my fiancee.
I met her through
this Internet service.
Uh, you-you pay
a whole bunch of money
but you get to choose from
these videos and then they bring
her over to the country
and she marries you.
- That's a good deal.
- Oh, I tell you, man.
These Eastern European types
they know how to take care
of their men.
Right. What happened?
Well, she left me for
this Vickers guy.
She comes to me one day
says she met this guy at work
they fell in love..
- Must've made you angry.
- 'Yeah, you bet it did.'
So you threaten to kill them
unless they pay you off.
No, no, no. I threatened
to turn her in to the INS.
Because she had lied about
all these things on her form.
She was in this country
under false pretenses.
How much
were you asking for?
Well, I just wanted
my money back.
The money I put up
to get her over here.
I saved all my receipts.
It was 25 grand.
Well, and 5 grand
for emotional suffering.
And what was her response?
She said they'd pay it.
She admitted she owed
me the money.
They were broke.
Any idea where they were
gonna get the money?
Jana said that Selby was gonna
get it from an old friend.
They guaranteed Badali
they'd have it
for him Monday in cash.
At least we know Selby's
sudden interest in the reunion.
He was protecting his wife.
It's kind of romantic.
- Noble, even.
- Ugh. Motive, even.
He must have asked
somebody for money
who really didn't
like him asking.
Yeah, nice work, Grace.
I need to see that list of all
the reunion attendees'
arrival times.
Oh, yeah. Here you go.
Thanks.
So, uh, you and Cho saw
some action, huh?
- Little bit, yeah.
- That's cool.
You have Gabe Nyland
arriving by plane
the day before the murder.
Are you sure that's right?
Yeah, there's an airfield
in Stratton the next town over.
I checked the arrival logs,
he flew in by private jet.
Be careful who you vote for
for lieutenant governor.
One of the candidates lies.
[instrumental music]
[knock on door]
[Nyland]
'Yes?'
It's agent Lisbon
and Patrick Jane.
We just have a few
follow-up questions for you.
Hi. How can I help?
Last night at the reception,
you said you'd just gotten in
but we know you flew
in the day before the murders.
Can you explain
the discrepancy for us?
Come on in.
I came a day early for
a private fundraising dinner.
I said I'd just arrived
because I didn't want
my classmates thinking
I'm up here shilling
during reunion weekend.
Nice room. Is it the, uh,
Presidential suite?
Something like that.
Is the bedroom nice?
How's the mattress?
Uh, it's adequate.
- Can I see it?
- Well, no.
- Why would you want to?
- Why not?
Because I'm entitled
to my privacy.
Hey!
Whoa.
Hello again.
Hi.
There was no inappropriate
relationship.
You call it
an inappropriate relationship.
The law calls it
soliciting sex from a minor.
She came to my door.
Had an idea
she wanted to discuss
about a youth voter effort
for my campaign.
I'm not going to discourage
some enthusiastic kid
who wants to get involved.
No, no. You hide 'em
in your bedroom.
I had to.
Media people follow me
everywhere I go now.
If I open that door and it's
some guerrilla photographer
our faces end up
on the internet
both of our lives
are ruined.
You're very good at this.
Selling a case with passion,
even though it holds no water.
Explains why you're
such a successful DA
It's the truth.
Well, that should
be easy to confirm.
Lisbon, could you have
the social worker
bring, uh, Tess in, please?
No, please.
This is on me.
She didn't ask for any of this.
You care about her.
You genuinely care
about her.
Well, she's very friendly..
...and diplomatic.
Diplomatic..
...and evasive,
like a politician..
...like her father.
That and you have
the same shape front teeth.
They are your real teeth,
aren't they?
[Lisbon]
'She's your daughter?'
Her mother was
a year behind me.
Tess was born a few weeks
before I graduated.
Families agreed
to keep it quiet.
But I've always done
right by Tess.
Come out to see her
whenever I can.
Discreetly, of course.
Did you ever see, Selby
when you visited?
Last year, at a gas station
just outside of town
We said a quick hello,
went our separate ways.
Maybe Selby found
out about Tess.
Threatened to expose you.
Not Selby Vickers.
He wouldn't threaten a fly.
A super nice guy.
He tried to do right
by people.
What'd you talk about
with Selby at the gas station?
Small talk. I told him,
I was gonna run
for lieutenant governor
and he offered
to print the campaign flyers,
free of charge.
Was he the same way
in high school?
Always.
Help you with your homework
he'd share his lunch with you
he was just happy
knowing that you liked him.
Even that thing with Logan,
he just did it to be popular.
I've answered
all your questions.
I think you should go now.
- Jane.
- What?
- Come on.
- Oh, Sorry.
Very nice to meet you.
Your politics are a roiling mess
of greed and cynicism
but you have
a lovely daughter.
[Jason Gleed singing
"Follow Me Now"]
♪ So everything's different ♪
♪ I guess that's okay ♪
♪ Cause those thoughts that used
to hold me down ♪
♪ Have all gone away ♪
♪ I feel like
I can take on the world ♪
♪ So come along for the ride ♪
♪ Or just get out of my way ♪
♪ Come on Come on ♪♪
[L.J.]
'Oh, him again.'
Oh.
I'll take care of it.
Mm.
[footsteps]
Mr. Jane, hello.
Willa, right?
Regional TV personality.
Yes.
Um, anything
I can help you with?
Oh, I'm just here
for the big game.
Football, I love it!
How goes
the investigation?
Oh, my colleagues are pursuing
several leads, uh..
...nothing definitive yet.
Mr. Jane, this is a weekend
of celebration.
Your presence is making
a few people uncomfortable.
Should I go away?
Should I leave
Selby and Jana un-avenged
because of some
low comfort levels?
- Is that what you're saying?
- No, no.
What are you saying then?
I.. never mind.
Okay.
Willa, I do have a question.
- Yes?
- How are the burgers?
The burg..
The burgers
are good. Very good.
[indistinct conversations]
Vice principal DeSouza
Do you mind
if I join you?
Wow, look at you.
All grown-up.
Sit down.
Tell me what you've
been up to these days.
Nice cover.
I didn't actually attend
this high school.
In fact, I didn't attend
any high school.
I'm with the CBI.
Oh, please, please.
These reunions
are insufferable.
What I wouldn't give
to be home on my couch
glass of wine, good book.
Well, I take it, you heard about
Selby Vickers and his wife.
Oh, yes.
That's-that's a tragedy.
Selby was a truly good kid.
You know, until that one
incident with Derek Logan.
Derek Logan was definitely
a different kinda duck.
He wore the same tattered
jacket, be it hot or cold.
Always hugged the wall
as he walked down a hallway.
He was off.
"off" isn't tolerated
in high school.
Well, certainly not in the 30
years I've been doing this job.
Right over there
is where it all happened.
Derek's folks sent him to
a shrink afterwards.
But it didn't help.
A month later,
they pulled him out of school.
That was the last
I heard of him.
Hmm.
Did Selby ever give
a reason why he did it?
You know, I asked him,
but he just shrugged.
You know, gave me that
teenage "I don't know."
[sighs]
How'd you catch him?
Derek was blindfolded, right?
Yes. He heard his attacker's
voice, though.
He thought it sounded
like Selby.
I confronted Selby.
He confessed quite readily
like the helpful,
honest boy he usually was.
It's very strange.
Hmm..
You want me to memorize
everything we have
on all 67 alumni
that showed up to the reunion?
Yes, I do.
And how would I do that?
It's easy.
You build a memory palace.
Um, I thought that was just
some card player's trick.
Well, it's multipurpose.
It's perfect for recalling
a large body of information.
All you need is a physical
location that you know well.
And you break it down in your
mind into smaller pieces
and link each one to a package
of the information..
Like this.
I walk in the door
and I'm greeted by
reunion chair, Willa Brock.
Former class president,
debate team captain
led the team to
three county championships.
Now a talk show host
in Chicago.
I sit down at the table
and catch up
with Dana Greer, swimmer,
now a realtor in Los Angeles
married to a gentleman
by the name of Arthur.
And so on and so forth.
Okay.
When you want to
remember the details
you close your eyes,
and in your mind
you walk around
your very own memory palace.
Yeah, but I-I can't learn all
this in just a couple of hours.
It comes very quickly
once you get the hang of it
and they'll be
wearing nametags.
But why? I mean,
why would I memorize all these--
It's fun.
This is some dubious scheme
that Lisbon doesn't know about
isn't it?
Yeah, you can count me out.
Sorry, you gotta do it.
Uh, no, I don't.
If you, uh, don't co-operate
I maybe forced to tell
Lisbon about you and Van Pelt.
Tell what?
There's nothing to tell.
Really?
Yeah. I don't know
what you're talking about.
Ah.
Contrary to very strict
CBI rules and regulations
you and Grace Van Pelt are
engaged in an illicit affair.
Nope.
You're being childish.
Don't tell Lisbon.
She'll report us to HR.
Well, she's a stickler.
They'll throw one of us
off the unit.
Better get to work.
[Los Del Rio singing
"Macarena"]
♪ Hey, macarena, ay! ♪
♪ Dale a tu cuerpo
alegria macarena ♪
♪ Que tu cuerpo es pa' darle
alegria y cosa buena ♪
♪ Dale a tu cuerpo
alegria macarena ♪
♪ Hey macarena, ay! ♪
♪ Macarena tiene un novio
que se llama ♪
♪ Que se llama
de apellido vitorino ♪
♪ Que en la jura
de bandera el muchacho ♪
♪ Es pa' darle
alegria y cosa buena ♪
♪ Dale a tu cuerpo
alegria macarena ♪
♪ Hey macarena, ay! ♪
School would be
so much more fun
if they started the day
with this every morning
instead of the, uh,
pledge of allegiance.
Or maybe they could, uh,
just integrate the two
into the "dance of allegiance."
We're taking a real flier here.
This better work.
- Timpani.
- No.
Huh. Really got me stumped
on that one.
I'm just guessing now.
We'd better get
this thing going
before people start leaving.
Have patience.
The fun will commence shortly.
[Ini Kamoze singing
"Hotstepper"]
♪ Na, na-na-na, na ♪
Hey, how's it going?
Nice to see you.
Long time.
Hey.
Coffee machine.
Stu McAlpine?
How goes it with my favorite
photo club president?
It goes great.
How goes it with you?
It goes whatever's
better than great.
You know,
I-I forgot your name.
It's, uh...
Derek Logan.
Yeah.
It's great to be back.
♪♪
Hi.
How are you?
Oh, yeah.
This is gonna be good.
I promise.
Great to see you, too, man.
Derek Logan.
I-I can't believe it.
Yeah, you've changed.
Well, who would've thought
that the girl who brought
four schools to their knees
in the high school
county debate finals
would be lost for words, huh?
You-you just
look so different.
Let's just chalk it up to
15 years' worth of solid hours
at the health club,
plus maybe a little bit of work.
You gotta look good
in my business, huh?
- You know what I mean?
- See it to believe it. Derek.
Hey, L.J., hey!
- Refrigerator.
- What?
Rancho Rosa versus Stratton.
The ball is on our 10,
2 seconds on the clock
Sims hands it off, bam!
You run 90 yards,
touchdown, Toros win.
Oh, you're-you're half right.
That was against Deerfield.
And it was a pass,
not a handoff
but it was close. Man!
That's Derek freakin' Logan!
Whoo!
I'm gonna, uh, make the rounds
to say some hellos
but it is great
to see you guys.
Wow!
[indistinct conversations]
- Wow, you're a natural.
- I can't do this.
You're doing it.
- You're ready for phase two?
- I can't.
Think of it like this,
you mess up, we blow the case
might tell Lisbon.
Oh, you're
a cold bastard, you know that?
[female# 1]
'Good evening, fellow Toros!'
[applauding]
Now is the part of the evening
you've all been waiting for
the achievement awards!
[applauding]
As voted by you
the 15th reunion class of
Rancho Rosa high.
[cheering]
Break a leg.
[Willa]
'Our first award.'
The "I can't believe
they're still together" award
which goes to
Dave Mercer
and Angie Diaz Mercer.
No surprises there,
am I right, gang?
What are you doing?
I'm a let you finish, Willa.
I, uh, just want to say
a few quick words.
Okay.
Just make it fast--
- Sure.
- Okay.
Uh, slight change of schedule.
We'll get right back to
the awards
but first, Derek Logan!
[applauding]
[male #1]
Yo, D!
Yeah.
Mm, uh, sure most of you are
scratching your heads
wondering why, uh,
why I'm here.
I came here tonight
because, uh...
Wanted to see how it felt like
to be here again.
'I'm not the same person
I was 15 years ago'
so when I walked in
that front door tonight..
...felt good.
[applauding]
Thank you.
But as soon as I set my eyes
on you people
I remember how it felt the last
time I walked out that door.
And I was that
sad, defeated kid again.
Sure, go ahead.
Feel sorry for me.
You should also
feel sorry for Selby.
May he, uh,
rest in peace.
'About a month ago,
Selby called me.'
'He'd been, uh, trying to track
me down for months, he said.'
'He wanted to apologize'
'and tell the truth about
what really happened that day.'
'The truth
that never came out.'
'You see,
Selby was a follower.'
Not a leader.
'And he did what he did'
'because somebody else
was there that day.'
somebody told him
to do what he did to me.
Yeah, that's right.
Hey, Gina, what's up?
He'll be fine. Just, um, uh...
give him an aspirin.
And I now know, who it was.
And that is the real reason
I am here.
I'm here to make you pay.
[murmuring]
Yeah, you-you ruined my life..
'...uh, that day.'
And I've spent 15 years
struggling to get it back.
And now, now I have.
Oh, yeah.
And I will have my revenge.
Payback is-is-is a bitch.
'like, uh, in that movie
with, um, uh...'
With uh,
Mel-Mel Gibson where they..
...where they kidnap his child.
Um, you know.
Uh, or is it the other one?
Uh, anyhow, um, that's me.
Enjoy the rest of your evening.
Go, Toros.
[applauding]
What-what do you
think you're doing?
Oh, the maid lent us this.
You still should tip her.
It's the right thing to do.
Must've been hard walking out
in the middle of
a big event you planned.
The speech was boring and I have
to get back to Chicago.
I have two shows
to prepare for on Monday.
I have a great idea
for your show.
Uh, "humiliating pranks and the
people who initiate them."
You could be
your own guest.
[laughing]
You-you have
no basis for that.
I just- I didn't want to have to
hear Derek go on and on about--
Your talk show
goes national soon.
So?
If Selby had gone to the media
with the story of
how you brutalized
a helpless boy
your big chance
would be history.
'So you arranged a meeting
with Selby to get the money.'
[Teresa]
'Jana showed up with him,
which you weren't expecting'
'so you killed them both.'
Oh, okay, I-I didn't have to
pay him or kill him.
[Willa]
'I, Selby didn't have
a stitch of proof'
'putting me
in that locker room.'
The media would've ignored him
as a crackpot.
"I have immortal longings
in me."
Do you remember that quote?
- Uh, uh, it's Shakespeare.
- Uh-huh.
I-I think it was the quote
in my yearbook photo.
And an apt one.
High school was a wonderful time
for you, wasn't it?
Yeah, you could say that.
Star student, class president,
champion debater.
You were at the top
of the social hierarchy.
Willa Brock was
the queen of the school.
Your world was perfect.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
But then something happened
and unsettled
that perfect world.
Derek Logan irked you,
somehow.
And you just couldn't let it
pass without a response
so you turned on the charm
you manipulated Selby
to do your bidding
knowing that he'd be thrilled
to help the popular girl.
The girl he was always
a little in love with.
And then you destroyed
Derek Logan.
To the delight
of your peers.
'And you enjoyed it.'
'cause you found it all
so easy and so empowering
and exciting, right?
All your success
at Rancho Rosa high.
This..
'...was Willa Brock's
crowning achievement.'
[whistles]
You've aged well.
It looks like Selby
took more than one photo
that day in the locker room,
didn't he?
Have a look at that.
Check that out.
[clicking]
This is Selby's proof.
But you didn't want to
pay him all that money
and risk him
blackmailing you again.
So you killed him
and his wife Jana.
Kinda poetic, how you were
done in by your own vanity.
Derek Logan told everyone
I let him touch me.
Like I ever would.
I was deeply humiliated.
So you ruined his life.
And Selby and Jana Vickers
had to die, too.
Selby falls for
that little polish girl
and suddenly grows a spine?
Things would have been perfect
if he just stayed
lonely and pathetic.
Close call.
If she'd have destroyed
the negative that Selby
had given her
we'd have no evidence
and no case.
It was a trophy.
It was a reminder
that the great Willa Brock
can crush anyone
that dares stand in her way
just like 15 years ago.
Yes, yes. Nobody advances
an inch from high school.
- You proved your point.
- Their instincts never change.
Selby and Derek
would both be grateful.
You two have
an open invitation
if you want to
join us at the 20th.
Hopefully,
we won't need to.
Keep it in the dojo, Phil.
One thing I don't get.
How did you persuade Rigsby
to play this charade?
I told him that you promised
to give him Monday off.
Not happening.
Well, that puts me
in an awkward position.
I-I-I-I held up my end
of the bargain.
[Extreme singing
"More Than Words"]
- Oh, god. I loved this song.
- Loved this song.
- I used to love this song.
- You love this song.
- Yeah.
- Obviously, you want to dance.
- With you? No.
- Oh, come on.
You can pretend that
I'm that mean, cold-hearted guy
that you used to worship
from afar, but never talked to.
♪ How easy it would be ♪
Hmm.
No funny stuff.
Really?
♪ More than words ♪
♪ Is all you have to do ♪
♪ To make it real ♪
♪ Then you wouldn't
have to say ♪
Trumpet?
♪ That you love me ♪
No.
♪ 'Cause I'd already know ♪♪
Stay tuned for
scenes from our next episode.
[theme music]